我叫巴里·艾伦  是现今世上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen, and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时
When I was a child,
看到自己的母亲被令人难以置信的东西杀害
I saw my mother killed by something impossible.
快跑  巴里
Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但我秘密地用自己的速度打击犯罪
but secretly, I use my speed to fight crime
寻找跟我一样的人
and find others like me.
终有一天  我会找到杀害母亲的凶手
And one day, I'll find who killed my mother...
妈妈
Mom!
让我父亲沉冤得雪
And get justice for my father.
我就是闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on The Flash...
昨晚  我在去停尸房的路上
Last night, on my way to the morgue,
我看到了些东西
I saw something.
出租车  别这样  我要迟到了
Taxi! Oh, come on! I'm gonna be late!
西蒙·斯塔格  记得他吗
Simon Stagg, remember him?
已经有大概半年没见到他了
Hasn't been seen in, like, six months.
你是说威尔斯知道斯塔格在哪吗
You're saying Wells knows where Stagg is.
不是  我是说威尔斯杀了他
No, I'm saying Wells killed him.
我的一份加密电子文件里有证据
I have evidence in a secure digital file
可以解释这一切
that will explain everything.
有一个大海啸正冲向城市呢
There is a tsunami heading for the city.
你必须离这里越远越好
You need to get as far away from here as possible.
我没有停止过想你
I have not been able to stop thinking about you.
快跑
Go!
出租车  出租车
Taxi! Taxi!
别这样  我要迟到了
Oh, come on! I'm gonna be late!
糟了
Oh, boy.
怎么了
Hey, what's going on?
-伙计  -我在  西斯科
- Dude? - Yeah, Cisco.
我在  这里
I'm...here...
出什么事了  你怎么停下来了
What happened? Why'd you stop?
我有点搞不清方向了
I just got a little disoriented.
你得把刚才的时间补上
Well, you need to make up some time, man.
你最好快点
You better hurry up.
快点  你在说什么呢
Hurry? What are you--
快点赶去停尸房呀
Hurry, as in get to the morgue.
停尸房  我已经去过了
The morgue? I was there.
就在昨天
Yesterday.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你得赶快过去
Come on, you gotta go.
闪电侠
第一季第十六集
巴仔  为什么这里都是水
Hey, Bar. What's with all the water?
这里的喷水系统坏了还是怎样
Did the sprinkler system go off or something?
没有啊  我查过所有的喷水器
What? No, I checked the sprinklers.
都完好无损
They're all intact.
但是水里有冰
But the water has ice in it.
法医身上的淤青
And the bruises on the coroner
也不仅仅只出现在脸上
aren't just on his face.
看看他的尸体
Check, look at his torso.
你怎么知道的
How the hell did you know that?
他是被冰雹砸死的
He was killed by hail.
我们得听听录音
We have to listen to the recording.
录音
Recording?
乔  这里有发现
Joe, we got something.
法医办公室正好装了
The coroner's office just installed
自动录音系统
an automated dictation system.
听听看这个
Listen to this.
不要再打了
Please...no more...
等你告诉我了  我再停
I'll stop when you tell me...
求你们停下
Just stop!
是谁杀了他
Who killed him?
是马克·马登
It's Mark Mardon.
他要报仇
He wants revenge.
我真的不想去
And I really don't wanna go.
他可是你哥哥  西斯科
He's your brother, Cisco.
要能选我才不要他呢
Not by choice.
就是个生日派对  能坏到哪去
Okay, well, how bad can a birthday party be?
我爸妈觉得丹堤放的屁都是香的
My folks think Dante's stink don't stink.
不管他做错多少事
Doesn't matter how much he screws up,
惹了多少次麻烦
or how many times he gets into trouble.
在我父母看来  他永远都是对的
In their eyes, he can do no wrong.
同时  他们也从未忘记提醒我
And yet, they never fail to remind me
我永远都是不对的
that I can do no right.
如果我跟你一起去呢
What if I came with you?
你说真的吗
What? Seriously?
真的  你都为我做了这么多了
Absolutely. You've done so much for me.
我也要为你付出一次
Let me be there for you for a change.
我还可以翻阅你的家庭相册
And I could look at old family photo albums
看看小时候不留长发的西斯科是什么样的
and see what little Cisco looks like without long hair.
那我还是不邀请你了
I'm rescinding your invite.
克莱德·马登有个哥哥
Clyde Mardon has a brother?
两兄弟都在坠机事件中活下来了
So, both Mardon brothers survived the plane crash
然后粒子加速器爆炸
and then the dark matter released
释放出的黑暗物质
by the Particle Accelerator explosion
本质上
affects them both in--
以同样的方式影响了他们
Virtually the same way.
没错
That's right.
除了马克和克莱德完全不一样
Only Mark's not like Clyde at all.
他的能力范围
He can do things that
你根本无法想象
you couldn't even imagine.
你是说他就像是某种
You mean he's sort of like a...
天气巫师
Weather wizard?
没错
Yeah.
三叉神经性头疼
Trigeminal headache?
艾伦先生
Mr. Allen.
借一步说话
A word please.
好的
Yeah.
你弄断了时间线  是不是
You ruptured the time continuum, didn't you?
你现在正经历着暂时的时间逆转
You're experiencing temporal reversion.
-没错  -这样多长时间了
- Yeah! - How long?
大概一天
A day and some change.
感觉就像把这天重新过了一遍
It's like I'm living it all over again.
那还好
Yeah, well that's good.
这说明你还没有造成太大的麻烦
That means there's not too much you could've messed up yet.
这一切是怎么发生的
How did this happen?
我不知道
I--I don't know.
我当时的速度达到了前所未有的高度
I mean,I was running faster than I've ever ran,
我第一次经历这一天的时候
and the first time that I lived this day
发生了很糟糕的事情
some really horrible things happened.
远处有巨浪袭来  然后
There was a tidal wave and...
别告诉我
No. Do not tell me.
我不想知道你在未来都经历了什么
I do not want to know anything about the future you experienced.
什么都不想知道
Nothing!
好吧  不过威尔斯博士  我
Okay, but Dr. Wells, I--
巴里
Barry.
时间
Time...
是一个极度脆弱的结构
is an extremely fragile construct.
不管是多小的偏差
Any deviation, no matter how small,
都能造成巨大的灾难
could result in a cataclysm.
现在你要这么做
Now here's what you're going to do.
你之前做过的一切
Everything you did before.
说过的所有话
Every word you uttered,
走过的每一个步伐
every step you took,
你都要重新做一遍
you're going to do again.
而且不能把这件事告诉任何人
And you're not going to tell anyone this happened.
早上好  威尔斯博士
Good day, Dr. Wells.
时间会决定我到底好不好  吉迪恩
Time will tell, Gideon.
给我看未来
Show me the future.
如您所愿
As you wish.
《中城时报》
闪电侠失踪  消失于危机之中
未来仍然完好无损  威尔斯博士
The future remains intact, Dr. Wells.
如果有任何变动
If anything changes,
马上提醒我
alert me immediately.
当然  博士
Of course, Doctor.
你怎么了
What's going on with you?
你是怎么弄明白停尸房发生的事情的
How'd you figure all that stuff out at the morgue?
一猜就中吧
Lucky guesses, I guess.
我可要告诉你
Look, I'm telling you,
我死也要抓到马登
I'm gonna get Mardon if it kills me.
乔...
Joe, um...
我有点事要去办
I gotta run an errand.
等会见  好吧
I'll see you later. All right?
没想到还有别人和我一样
I didn't know there was anyone else like me.
我会逃出这里
I'm gonna break out of here!
我要制造一道大浪
I'm gonna create a tidal wave
毁掉整个城市
that destroys your entire city!
那个  我还是不太明白
So, I still don't understand.
你怎么找到他的
How did you find him?
我只是突然灵光一闪
I just had a hunch.
这一定破纪录了
That's gotta be some kind of record.
是啊
Yeah.
看来我没有借口
Well, there goes my excuse
不去参加我哥哥的生日了
for bailing on my brother's birthday.
你意识到你刚才做了什么吗
Do you have any idea what you've just done?
是的  我知道
Yeah, I do.
我刚拯救了很多生命
I just saved a lot of lives.
我警告过你不要扰乱时间线
I warned you not to mess with the timeline.
威尔斯博士  如果你让我
Dr. Wells, if you would just let me
告诉你未来会发生什么
tell you what was gonna happen,
你就会明白我为什么这么做了
you'd understand why I did this.
不管你认为你避免了什么悲剧
Whatever tragedy you think you've just averted,
或迟或早总还是会发生
time will find a way to replace it
相信我  巴里
and trust me, Barry,
接下来的可能会更糟糕
the next one could be much worse.
桑蒂尼阁下  他们来了
Don Santini, they're here.
快走
Move it.
墙板不错啊  红木的吗
Oh, love the paneling. Mahogany?
真高兴你的房子是木质的
So glad your house is made out of wood.
看着它燃烧一定很爽
It's gonna be a pleasure watching it burn.
爽快
Refreshing!
你回到中城来干什么  史纳特
What are you doing back in Central City, Snart?
这是我的城市
This is my city.
我们的城市
Our city.
我说过如果再见到你
I told you if I ever saw you again
我就要让你痛哭了
I'd put the hurt on you.
你到处兴风作浪  这对生意不好
You stir up trouble. Trouble is bad for business.
是时候让你的家族收拾行李了
It's time for you and your family to pack up.
离开城市  退休找个暖和的地方呆着
Leave town. Retire to warmer climates.
剧终
Finito.
如果我们拒绝呢
And if we don't?
你们都会被冻住
You will all freeze.
或是燃烧
Or burn.
我听说过你们的枪
I heard about your guns.
我还听说你们把枪弄丢了
I also heard that you lost them.
那么  告诉我  史纳特
So, tell me, Snart.
你和你那喷火朋友
What the hell are you and your pyro friend
没有了那些花哨武器还能干什么
gonna do without your fancy weapons?
干这个
This.
这才有趣啊
Now that was fun!
有趣  有趣  有趣
Fun. Fun. Fun.
滚吧
Go.
告诉其他桑蒂尼家族的人
Tell the rest of the Santini family
现在有了一位新教父
there's a new Godfather.
他的名字叫寒冷队长
And his name is Cold.
你父母在那个蛋糕上还真是大手笔
Your parents really went all out with the cake.
这可是丹堤的生日
Oh, well...it is Dante's birthday.
一年中最重要的日子
The most important day of the year.
我儿子被邀请到卡内基音乐厅演奏
Mi hijo was invited to play Carnegie Hall
当时他只有十三岁
when he was just 13 years old.
他们邀请的是整个乐队  妈妈
They invited the entire band, Mama.
那也改变不了这事的重要性
That doesn't make it any less worthwhile.
怎么样  兄弟
What's up, man?
真高兴你能来
Glad you could make it.
当然了
Of course.
你好  我是丹堤
Hi, I'm Dante.
这是我朋友  凯特琳
This is my friend, Caitlin.
你好  凯特琳
Hi, Caitlin.
生日快乐  丹堤
Happy birthday, Dante.
谢谢你
Thank you.
给  我给你买的
Here, I... I got you this.
我觉得你会喜欢的
I think you'll really like it.
-是个...  -谢了  兄弟
- It's... - Thanks, man.
-不谢  -失陪
- Yeah. - Excuse me.
我不明白
I don't get it.
我已经尽力跑得和发生时空逆转时一样快
I've been running just as fast as I was when it happened.
但什么也没发生 我还在这里
And nothing, I'm still here.
很多事情都可能引发虫洞
Any number of things could've triggered the wormhole
让你可以回到一天前
that allows you to repeat your day.
你的情感  当时的环境
Your emotions, your circumstances,
你的皮质醇水平  都有可能
your cortisol levels, all of the above.
那个  我的肾上腺素倒是很高
Well, I mean, my adrenaline was super high
因为爱瑞丝还有整个城市...
since Iris and the entire city...
不不不
No, no, no.
别说细节  我告诉过你
No details. I told you.
好吧  我很抱歉
All right, I'm sorry,
但是马克·马登已经关在管道监狱里了
but Mark Mardon's already locked in the pipeline
也没什么坏事发生
and nothing bad has happened.
目前而已
Yet.
警探
Detective.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
你准备什么时候告诉我
So when were you planning on telling me
你已经抓到了马登
you took down Mardon?
我只是还没找到机会
I--I just haven't had a chance yet.
你是说你分神了吗
You got sidetracked, you mean?
不是  乔  你别生气啊
No, Joe, you can't be mad.
我没生气
I'm not mad.
但我很好奇
But I am curious.
我是说  你在犯罪现场表现的很奇怪
I mean, you were acting so weird at the crime scene.
我总是那么奇怪
I always act weird.
好吧  怪人
Okay. Weirdo.
听着  乔  只不过是
Look, Joe, there are just
有些事情我不能告诉你
some things that I can't tell you,
你必须相信我
and you're gonna have to trust me.
琳达·帕克
你好啊  琳达  没错  我知道
Hey, Linda. Yeah, I know.
真是抱歉  我一时忘记了
I'm so sorry. I--I lost track.
我马上就过去
I'm gonna head that way now.
好的  再见
All right, bye.
我与琳达约好了吃午饭
I have a lunch date with Linda.
我得走了
I gotta run.
我想你也不会告诉我吧
And I don't suppose you're gonna fill me in either?
不会
No.
真是棒  丹堤
Que linda, Dante!
这可是位天选之子
Well, here is one who was touched by God.
我有些生疏了
Ah, I was a little rusty.
有阵子没弹了
I haven't played in a while.
好吧
Oh, well...
如果这是你生疏时候的水平
If that was what you sounded like rusty,
真不敢想象你熟练时候的水平
I can't imagine what you sound like when you've practiced.
为了你  我会日夜练习
Oh, for you, I'd practice morning, noon, and night.
那意味着你早上真的得起来
That means you'd actually have to get up in the morning.
妈妈告诉我你还在
So, Mom tells me you're still working
尖端科研实验室工作呢
at S.T.A.R. Labs, huh?
是啊  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
没什么  老弟
No reason, man.
看起来你是找不到其他工作了吧
Guess it was just hard to find another job, huh?
我就没在找
Oh, I wasn't looking.
我挺喜欢在尖端科研实验室工作的
I actually like working at S.T.A.R. Labs.
我们没有西斯科可不行
And we couldn't do what we do without Cisco.
他很忠诚
Oh, he's loyal.
就像条狗
Just like a dog.
别这样  那么认真干什么  小妹妹
Oh, come on. Why are you so serious, mi hija?
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
我来了  再次抱歉了
I am here. So sorry, again.
饶你一次  鉴于你从来不迟到
Well, you get a pass considering you're never late.
你最近是怎么了
What's going on with you lately?
没什么
Nothing.
说吧
Come on.
好歹给我一点信任吧
Give me a little credit here.
我最近需要应付的事
I've just been dealing with
比较多
a lot of things lately.
我喜欢你  琳达  我们也很合得来
I like you, Linda. And we really get along.
恋爱关系应该不只是合得来那么简单吧
Relationships should be more than just getting along.
你应该从心里渴望拥有我
Your heart should ache for me.
是这样吗
Does it?
你不生我的气吗
You're not upset with me?
谁都没有错
No one did anything wrong.
我真的对你很有感觉  琳达
I really do feel a lot for you, Linda.
只是...
It's just...
只是没有对那个人的感觉多
Just not as much as you feel for someone else.
去找她吧
Go get her.
闪电侠  以极速闯入我们的生活
"闪电侠  以极速闯入我们的生活"
"The Flash, speeding his way into our lives."
有点太骚气了  不是吗
It's a little bit on the nose, don't you think?
我有东西要给你看
I have something to show you.
西蒙·斯塔格  记得他吗
Simon Stagg, remember him?
已经有大概一年没见到他了
Hasn't been heard from in nearly a year.
爱瑞丝  布里奇先生  你好
Hey, Iris. Mr. Bridge, hi.
我们认识吗
Do I know you?
不  我们还没...
Oh, no, we haven't met yet...
正式见过面...
fully, you know, um...
爱瑞丝  我们能谈谈吗
Iris, can I talk to you for a second?
好的
Yeah, sure.
-我们晚点再谈  -好的
- We'll catch up later. - Yeah.
认识你很高兴  奇怪的年轻人
Nice meeting you, strange young man.
你和琳达还好吧
Is everything okay with you and Linda?
不  我们结束了
No, that's done.
对不起
Oh, I--I am so sorry.
没关系的  我们还会是朋友
No, no, no, it's okay. We're gonna be friends.
是的  不  那样也不错
Um, yeah, no, it's gonna be awesome.
对了  你...
Uh...anyway, are you...
你明天有空吗
are you free tomorrow?
想不想一起喝杯咖啡
Do you want to get some coffee
我们可以随便聊聊
and we can just talk and just
说说最近发生的事...
tell each other stuff...
我说不好  就是我们
I don't know, stuff we got
周围的那些八卦  你说呢
rolling around in there, you know? I don't know.
好啊  可以
O-okay, yeah, sure.
听起来不错
It sounds great.
好的  太好了
Okay, great. Great!
好吧  明天见
All right, I'll see you.
我知道你认为哈里森·威尔斯
I know you think Harrison Wells
与西蒙·斯塔格的失踪有关
had something to do with Simon Stagg's disappearance,
不过你错了
but you're wrong.
-好啊  -好啊  老兄
- Hey. - Oh, hey, man.
谢谢你来见我
Thanks for meeting me here.
尽管...  你喝不醉
Even though... you can't get drunk.
不用担心
No worries.
你今天过得怎么样
So, how was your day?
很好  不过...
Great. But...
琳达和我分手了
Linda and I did break up.
我还是头一次听到有人用"很好"
That's the first time I ever heard anyone
来形容分手的
use the word "Great" to describe a break-up.
我有种感觉  我将要
I have a feeling that I'm about to
和一个特别的人开始新的恋情
move forward with someone really special.
好吧  真有你的  巴里
Okay. Go ahead, Barry.
你好
Hi.
通常我不会这样做的
I don't normally do this,
但我一直在注意你...
but I was watching you, and...
能请你喝杯酒吗
can I buy you a drink?
说真的  我很受宠若惊  不过我...
I mean, I'm really flattered, but I...
其实  我在跟他说话
Actually, I was talking to him.
抱歉
Um... I'm--I'm sorry,
你说  你在跟我说话吗
you said--you said you were talking to me?
是的  我刚才跟我朋友说
Yeah, I just told my friends over there
我觉得你很帅
that I thought you were cute
他们说我不敢过来
and they dared me to come over here
跟你说话  所以...
and talk to you, so...
请跟我聊聊吧
please talk to me.
好的  我想我可以
Yeah. Yeah, I suppose I can talk to you
跟你聊一会儿
for a little bit.
是啊  我这就走
Yeah, no, I was just leaving.
争口气
Make me proud.
我叫丽萨
I'm Lisa, by the way.
我叫西斯科
Hi, Cisco.
我来城里参加水星实验室的研讨会
I'm just in town for this symposium at Mercury Labs.
真的吗  你是从事什么工作的
Really? You, what do you do?
我是建筑工程师
Oh, I'm a structural engineer.
干嘛这么惊讶
Why do you look so surprised?
女孩不能当工程师吗
Can't a girl be an engineer?
不是  当然可以  只是...
No, of course. That's...
你看起来不像个工程师
You just don't look like an engineer.
我的长相不由我说了算
I can't help how I look.
我是说  很好
I--I mean, it's good.
你长得很漂亮
It's a-- it's a good look.
你很漂亮
It's a great look.
你也不赖啊
Well, you don't look so bad yourself.
你是在跟我玩什么恶作剧吗
Am I being pranked right now?
你认为呢
What do you think?
真不敢相信  今天一开始我过得
I can't believe this. The day started out
糟透了  不过现在真是太棒了
pretty terrible, but now it's turning out pretty damn good.
我也这么觉得
I'll say.
看呐
Look at this.
这些都是好东西
These are nice things.
我们借住在别人的地方
Oh, we're just squatting.
我们
We?
是的
Yeah.
我和我哥哥
Me and my brother.
你好  西斯科
Hello, Cisco.
你对我妹妹到底有什么企图
What exactly are your intentions with my sister?
拜托
Oh, come on.
我早就该想到
I should've known better.
我没那么幸运
I am not that lucky.
别因为我亲了你妹妹就杀我好吗
Please don't kill me for kissing your sister.
你亲了他吗
You kissed him?
你又不是老爸  兰尼
You're not dad, Lenny.
我知道  老爸在牢里
I know. Dad's in jail.
十足的好榜样
Sterling role model.
你想怎么样  史纳特
What do you want, Snart?
枪  我想要能制热或制冷的
Guns. Heat and cold, to be precise.
你休想让我为你研制武器
There's no way I am making weapons for you.
想也别想
Never again.
米克
Mick.
我知道我会竭尽全力
I know I would do everything in my power
保护自己的家人
to protect my family.
问题是  你会吗
The question is, will you?
丹堤
Dante.
丹堤  保持冷静
Dante, just keep cool, okay?
-让我来搞定  -是吗
- Let me do my thing. - Oh, really?
怎么  你要用你的
And what? You're gonna save us
机械工程技术拯救我们俩吗
with your mechanical engineering skills?
目前看来  我的技能是唯一可以
Right now, my skills are the only things
让我们活命的东西
keeping us alive,
所以如果我是你的话  我就闭嘴
so if I were you, I would shut up.
你闭嘴
You shut up!
她在这啊
Ah! There she is.
我好想念这个宝贝
I missed this baby.
给你了  都弄好了  你会放了我们吗
Here it is. All finished. You gonna let us go now?
要知道  你给我做的第一把枪
You know, I took the first gun you made me apart
被我拆了几十次
dozens of times.
搞清楚它是怎么运转的
Learned how it ticked.
哪里应该有什么
What went where.
你以为可以篡改撞针
Thought you could tamper with the firing pin
而不被我发觉吗
without me noticing.
想得美  小子
Nice try, kid.
-对了  -兰尼
- Yes. - Lenny?
我的枪呢
Where's my gun?
女生也得保护自己
Girl's gotta defend herself.
再说了  为什么只有你们俩可以找乐子
Besides, why should you two have all the fun?
我妹妹需要一把枪
My sister needs a weapon.
跟她个性相匹配的
Something that suits her personality.
给我做把既漂亮又有伤害力的
Make me something pretty and toxic,
就跟我一样
like me.
喷金子的怎么样
How about something with gold?
金子
Gold.
一个加厚羊角甜甜圈
One incredibly heavy cronut
一杯美式咖啡  多加一份浓缩咖啡
and one Americano with an extra shot.
-正是你喜欢的  -正是我喜欢的
- Just the way you like it. - Just the way I like it.
是啊  我懂
Yeah, I know.
我懂你  爱瑞丝
I know you, Iris.
你怎么回事啊
So... what is going on with you?
表现得好像圣诞节提前来了一样
You're acting like Christmas came early.
是啊  不  是有点这样的感觉
Yeah, no, I guess it did, kind of.
爱瑞丝
Look, Iris...
我还是一直很想你
I still think about you all the time
我知道你也一直在想我
and I know you've been thinking about me too,
所以我们都别想了
so let's just stop thinking
行动起来吧
and start doing.
-巴里  -我知道
- Barry... - I know.
现在我们俩的时机都不好
I know that we both have awful timing,
但我们注定要
but we were meant to be--
巴里  你在说什么
Barry, what are you talking about?
你和我
You and me.
我们互相喜欢
We like each other.
巴里  我们已经谈过这个了
Barry, we've been over this.
行吗  我什么都没变
Okay? Nothing has changed for me.
不  已经变了
No, but it has.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
我就是
I just...
我就是知道一些东西
I just know some stuff somehow.
我不知道  就像
I don't know, maybe it's like
超能力之类的  但是
ESP or something, but--
巴里
Barry.
我爱艾迪  懂吗
I love Eddie, okay?
抱歉  自圣诞节以来  我并未
I'm sorry, but nothing has changed for me
发生任何改变
since Christmas.
你不能总拿这个来问我
And you can't keep springing this on me.
好吗  你一直让我
Okay? It's not fair
当坏人来拒绝你
that you keep making me the bad guy
不公平
who keeps telling you no.
怎么了  不闪电进入了
What? No whoosh-in?
我需要走走
I needed the walk.
发生什么事了
What happened?
没什么
Nothing...
琳达  爱瑞丝
Linda...Iris...
其实我不想说
I don't want to talk about it, actually.
好吧
Okay.
你联系过西斯科吗
Have you talked to Cisco?
我一直在打他的手机
I've been trying him on his cell,
但他都没接
but he's not answering.
有点担心他
Kind of... worried about him.
他过了个糟糕的晚上
He had a rough night.
相信我  情况有好转
Trust me, it got better.
乔  怎么了
Hey, Joe. What's up?
史纳特回来了
Yeah, Snart's back.
等等  寒冷队长回来了
Wait, Cold is back?
是啊  有人看到他在桑蒂尼犯罪家族赌场
Yeah, he was spotted at the Santini crime family casino.
如果他在袭击桑蒂尼家族  我们就可以
If he's hitting the Santinis, we could be looking at
看到帮派战争开场了
the beginning of a mob war.
今天真是越来越精彩了  不是吗
Well, this day just keeps getting better, doesn't it?
你杀了我哥哥
You killed my brother.
你不该惹我的家人
You shouldn't have messed with my family.
这可真是有趣
That's funny.
我本打算说一样的话
I was gonna say the same thing about ours.
会闪光的
All that glitters...
这真恶心
This is sick.
是你想我们更常待在一起
Well, you wanted us to spend more time together.
我们还要再来多少回  史纳特
How many times are we gonna go through this, Snart?
直到最强者胜出为止
Until the best man wins!
放下枪
Drop the gun!
你我都知道你不会对她做什么
We both know you're not going to do anything to her.
随便介绍一下  这是我妹妹
Oh, by the way, meet my baby sister.
丽萨  这是闪电侠
Lisa, Flash.
闪电侠  这是丽萨
Flash, Lisa.
西斯科一直都在忙
Cisco has been very, very busy.
除非你想让我
Unless you want me to mail
寄一块他的冰冻碎片去他家
small, frozen pieces of him back to his family,
否则你最好放开她
I'd take your hands off her.
放他走  史纳特
Let him go, Snart.
我会考虑的
I'll think about it.
巴仔
Barr.
目击者称看到了闪电侠
Witnesses reported seeing The Flash.
他们说你当场抓住了史纳特
They said you had Snart dead to rights
但你放走了他
but you let him go?
为什么
Why?
西斯科
Cisco.
在史纳特和他妹妹手上
Snart and his sister have him.
不是吧
Oh, man.
好吧  回尖端科研实验室去
Okay. Get to S.T.A.R. Labs.
我会尽快去那
I'll get there when I can.
好
All right.
艾伦
Allen.
艾迪  我
Yeah, Eddie, I--
离爱瑞丝远点
Stay away from Iris.
怎么回事
What the hell is going on here?
如果你们俩要吵架的话  出去吵
Hey, if you two have a beef, you take it outside.
你知道最糟糕的是什么吗  巴里
You know what the worst part is, Barry?
我以为我们是朋友
I thought you and I were friends.
这是西斯科和史纳特的妹妹上车的录像
So there's Cisco getting into a car with Snart's sister.
车牌被冰遮住了
And the license plate is iced over.
好了  威尔斯博士  你说得对
All right, Dr. Wells, you were right.
我耍了时间一把
I--I--I screwed with time
现在时间反过头来耍我了
and now time is screwing with me.
寒冷队长回来了
Cold is back,
他绑架了西斯科  爱瑞丝
he kidnapped Cisco, and Iris is--
在你引起另一次时间混乱前
Stop right there before you cause another disruption
就此打住吧
to the timeline.
拜托了  威尔斯博士
Please, Dr. Wells.
拜托了  我得跟人谈谈
Please, I have to talk to someone.
说吧
Go ahead.
今天的早前版本是
In the previous version of today,
辛格队长会受重伤
Captain Singh is seriously injured,
乔处于危险中
Joe is in danger,
爱瑞丝会说她喜欢我
and Iris said she had feelings for me.
而现在西斯科命悬一线
And now Cisco's life is on the line,
爱瑞丝完全不知道她坦白了那些想法
and Iris has no idea she confessed those feelings.
但她还是有这样的想法  对吧
But she still has them, right?
潜意识  巴里
The unconscious mind, Barry,
是很强大的
it-- it's a powerful thing.
需要实实在在发生的灾难
It sounds like it took this apparent disaster
来开启那些情感的出口
to jar those feelings loose
而没有了灾难  那些情感
and without a disaster, those feelings
就依然深埋心底
remain deeper down.
无法触及了
Unaccessed.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我以为通过阻止马登
I thought that I was helping people
我可以帮助人们
by stopping Mardon.
是的  但你的这种新能力
Yes, but this new ability of yours,
巴里  很危险
Barry, is dangerous.
你只是重返了一天
You only traveled back in time one day.
如果你重返几十年前呢
What if you traveled back decades?
几世纪呢
Centuries?
想象下你会造成的混乱
Imagine the havoc you could wreak.
但不久的未来我就会有机会
But I will have the opportunity
及时回到过去
to travel back in time in the near future
救我妈妈
and save my mom.
或者你是说我不该这样
Or...you're saying I shouldn't?
我是说
I'm saying
如果你妈妈活着的话
how many more people could die
有多少人会死呢
if your mother lives?
你们找到西斯科了吗
Did you guys find Cisco?
很多人认为火焰最炽热的部分
Most people think the hottespart of the flame
是白色的部分
is the white part.
他们错了
They're wrong.
你要赞美它们  还是要喝掉它们
You gonna admire those or you gonna drink 'em?
两者皆要
Both.
如果他们想放我们走  早就放了
是  我知道
记得梅琳达·托雷斯吗
你的高中女友
还是我的至爱
在我们开始约会之前
她和我说她喜欢你
梅琳达·托雷斯喜欢我吗
我和她说你想做个牧师
I told her you wanted to become a priest.
让她心碎
Broke her heart.
你为什么这么做
Why'd you do that?
因为我嫉妒你  老弟
Because I was jealous of you, man.
即使那样  我
I mean, even then I...
我知道我生活的走向
I knew exactly where my life was headed.
-停滞不前  -丹堤
- Nowhere. - Dante.
不是这样的
That's not true.
我住在家里
I live at home.
而我的垃圾工作也没有薪水
And I work a crap job for no pay.
但你还是成为了爸妈最爱的孩子
Yeah, but you still manage to be Mom and Dad's favorite.
我都不知道是为什么
I don't even know why.
是因为他们  他们仍然把我
It's because they-- they still think of me
看成他们的儿子  那个音乐会钢琴家
as their son, the concert pianist.
但是你  他们永远不明白你的天赋
But you, man, they never understood your talents.
永远也不明白你追逐的激情  不管是什么
Never understood that you pursued your passion no matter what.
而我  我只是太害怕去尝试
And me, I was just too scared to even try.
我从未为自己的人生争取过
直到现在
丹堤  丹堤
Dant-- Dante...
不
No!
米克
Mick!
米克  冷静点
Mick, calm down!
米克  我们需要他们
Mick! We need them!
米克  宝贝
Mick? Baby?
你好像饿了
It sounds like you're hungry.
我们去吃点晚餐吧
How about you and I grab some dinner?
我喜欢你  孩子
I like you, kid.
你很聪明
You're smart.
你凭一己之力摆脱了卑微的身份
You pulled yourself up from humble beginnings.
你看上去像是个好弟弟
You seem like a good brother.
你也是
You too.
这点值得商榷
Debatable.
回答我一个问题
You answer one question for me,
我就让你和你哥哥走
I'll let you and your brother walk.
什么问题
What's the question?
闪电侠是谁
The Flash. Who is he?
我发誓  他总是带着面具
I swear... he always wears a mask.
不
No!
不  住手
No! Stop!
这是一级冻伤
This is first degree frost bite.
只要你哥哥得到妥善处理  就能恢复
Your brother could recover with proper treatment.
如果没的话  他全身的肌腱  血管和神经
If not, all his tendons, blood vessels, and nerves
就会被冻住
will freeze.
他的手指就要被切掉
His fingers will need to be amputated.
拉蒙家的假日就再也没协奏曲可听了
No more concertos for the Ramon family holidays.
告诉我  闪电侠是谁
Now tell me, who is The Flash?
卫星温度记录上什么也没有
There's nothing on the satellite thermography.
你说得对  这都是我的错
You were right. This is all my fault.
怎么会是你的错
How is this your fault?
别气馁  巴里  我们会把西斯科救回来的
Brave heart, Barry. We'll get Cisco back.
我回来了
I'm back.
天呐  你没事吧
Oh, my God. Are you okay?
我们刚才很担心你
We were so worried.
发生了什么事
What happened?
你怎么逃出来的
How did you escape?
我没逃
I didn't.
史纳特就这么放你走吗  为什么
Snart just let you go? Why?
他  他折磨我哥哥
He... he tortured my brother.
他说他要杀了他
And he said he was gonna kill him
如果我不
if I didn't...
如果我不告诉他
if I didn't tell him...
告诉他什么
Tell him what?
告诉他闪电侠的真实身份
Who The Flash really is.
我  老实说  他们
I, honestly, man, they...
他们本来可以杀掉我的
they could've killed me.
但是他们要杀我哥哥
But they were gonna kill my brother.
我不能让他这么做
I couldn't let him do that.
对不起  巴里
I'm sorry, Barry.
-不  -真的很对不起
- No. - I'm so sorry.
是我让你陷入那种险境
I put you in that position.
我应该说对不起
I'm the one who's sorry.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我没资格留在这
I don't deserve to be here.
我不能让你们陷入危险
I won't be the one to put you in jeopardy.
不能再有下次
Not again.
绝对不能再有下次
Never again.
你怎么来了
What?
真是令人惊讶啊
What a surprise.
正如今晚艾迪在犯罪现场
As big a surprise as Eddie punching Barry
揍巴里一样令人大吃一惊
at a crime scene this evening.
天呐  巴里还好吧
Oh, my God. Is Barry okay?
没事  他愈合得很快
Yeah. He... heals fast.
爱瑞丝  这事变得很复杂
Look, Iris. This got complicated.
我知道  对不起
I know. I'm sorry.
巴里太迟了  我已经和艾迪一起了
Barry was too late. I'm with Eddie.
我来问问你
Let me ask you something.
你到底爱谁
Who do you love?
我当然爱艾迪
I mean, I love Eddie.
好  那你要让他们相信这点
Okay. You need to make them believe that,
因为现在  我想他俩都不相信这点
because right now, I'm not sure either one of them does.
好吗
Okay?
好
Okay.
我有和你说过你有多明理多棒吗
Did I ever tell you how wise and amazing you are?
还不够
Not enough.
晚点见
See you later.
-我来得不是时候吗  -是的
- Bad time? - Yes, actually.
别担心  我很快就会离开这里
Don't worry, I'll be out of here soon.
在你永远摆脱这里之前
Well, before you shuffle off forever,
我能给你看点东西吗
may I show you something?
我明白  我失败了
I get it. I failed.
不不不  你是个非常聪明的人  西斯科
No, no, no. Now, you're an incredibly clever guy, Cisco.
不如你来告诉我
So why don't you tell me
我为什么带你来这里
why would I bring you down here?
因为那晚我们都失败了
Because we all failed that night.
但是我们一直继续
But we kept going.
我们一直继续守护彼此
We kept trying to protect each other,
还有巴里
and Barry,
尽管碰到挫折
in spite of the setbacks.
在两个
Making a choice
你爱的人当中做出选择
between two people you love,
这是你面对过最艰难的困境
that is the hardest dilemma you will ever face.
你不必担心我
Well, you won't have to worry about me
会再次做出错误的决定
making the wrong decision again.
今天你已经证明了  拉蒙先生
All you proved today, Mr. Ramon,
你只是个人类
is that you're human.
今天你已经证明了
All you proved today
你爱你的哥哥
is that you love your brother.
我们所有的人要你留下的原因是
And the reason that we all want you to stay
因为我们也爱你
is that we love you too.
我虽然没做过父亲
Now, I am not a parent,
但是  从很多方面来说
but, in many ways,
你已经让我知道了
you have shown me what it's like
有儿子的感觉
to have a son.
各位  你们得过来一下
Guys, you should get up here.
去吧
Shall we?
赌场不是目标
The casino wasn't the target.
那他为什么要那么做
Then why did he do it?
赌场都会储备大量现金
Casinos keep tons of cash on hand
以便老客申请借款  更不用说
to cover their markers, not to mention
他们所赚到的那些钱
the money that they make.
但如果他们遭到袭击
But if they're under attack,
按照规定他们要把钱放到赌场外的地方
the protocol is to relocate the money outside the casino.
所以  这就是史纳特一直在计划的
So, that was Snart's plan all along.
-引发事端  -好吧  钱到哪了
- To trigger the move. - Okay, where is it now?
做好准备  有人来了
Get ready, we got company.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you...
巴里
Barry.
我们得谈谈
We have to talk.
我知道西斯科告诉了你我是谁
I know Cisco told you who I am.
不能怪他把你供出来了
Can't really blame the kid for giving you up.
选你还是选他哥哥
You or his brother? Come on!
我让他处在两难境地
I put him in a tight spot.
现在轮到你了
Same kind I got you in right now.
既然我知道你是谁  你就阻止不了我了
Can't really stop me now that I know who you are.
我可以很快地把你扔进我们的私人监狱
I could speed you to my own private prison
在那你永远都见不到阳光
where you'll never see the light of day.
你可以这么做  但那样的话
You could, but then I won't be around
我就不能终止我所上传的东西
to stop my own private uplink
它会让全世界知道你的真实身份
that'll broadcast your identity to the world.
所以  最关键的问题来了
So, the million dollar question.
你现在要拿我怎么办  巴里·艾伦
What to do with me now, Barry Allen?
我不会让你
I won't let you keep stealing
想偷什么就偷什么  想干什么就干什么
whatever you want, whenever you feel like it.
-我要阻止你  -你做不到
- It needs to end. - Can't do that.
我就是干这个的
It's what I do.
那就换份新工作
Then find a new line of work.
不想换
Don't want to.
为什么
Why is that?
和你要抓像我这样的人一样的原因
The same reason you keep running after guys like me.
肾上腺素  追捕的快感
The adrenaline. The thrill of the chase.
我喜欢这种游戏
I love this game.
而且我也很擅长
And I'm very good at it.
那就去别的地方玩
Then go play it somewhere else.
离开中城
Leave Central City.
也做不到
Can't do that either.
我喜欢在这玩
I love it here.
这座城市是我的家
This city is my home.
你见识过我的本事
You've seen what I can do.
你知道我能够阻止你
You know that I can stop you.
你想要用光你的运气
You want to keep pushing your luck,
随你的便
go for it.
不过从现在开始
But from here on out,
不会再有人死了
no one else dies.
如果你真像自己说的那么厉害
If you're as good as you say you are,
你不需要杀任何人
you don't have to kill anyone
就能得到自己想要的东西
to get what you want.
说得没错
That's true.
如果你  或者任何
And if you, or anyone
你们犯罪团伙里的人
in your rogues' gallery
再敢伤害我的朋友或家人
goes near any of my friends or family again,
不管你会把我的身份告诉谁
I don't care who you tell my identity to.
我都会除掉你
I'm putting you away.
我想你的秘密是安全的
I guess your secret's safe...
闪电侠
Flash.
暂时安全
For now.
我想你是不会
Oh, I don't suppose you'd give me a ride
送我回城的  对吧
back to town, would you?
无赖帮
The Rogues.
真好笑
Cute.
我
I...
我很抱歉  伙计
I am so sorry, pal.
我不愿意打人
It's not like me to hit anyone.
我不知道自己是怎么了
I don't know what came over me.
谢谢你这么说  艾迪  没关系的
Thanks, Eddie. It's--it's okay.
你真可怜  我都不知道
You poor thing. I had no idea.
是吗
Is that right?
你不知道什么
What exactly did you have no idea about?
我刚才正在跟爱瑞丝和艾迪解释
I was just explaining to Iris and Eddie
你的闪电精神病
about your Lightning Psychosis.
我的什么
My what now?
闪电精神病
Your Lightning Psychosis.
就是你最近反常的举动
How your recent odd behavior
都是因为被闪电击中后的副作用
is a side effect of being struck by lightning.
心情不定  突然出现的好感
Mood swings, sudden outbursts of affection,
以及一些判断失误
and other lapses in judgment.
这些症状他都有
He has had all of those things.
他跟我说自己有了超能力
He told me that he had ESP.
是的  这是一种非常罕见的
Yeah, it's a very uncommon
神经方面的情况
neurological phenomenon.
我们才刚刚开始
We're really only just now
研究这种疾病的解药
starting to research in kerauno-medicine.
这就是巴里
That's why Barry's been
经常待在尖端科研实验室的原因
spending so much time at S.T.A.R. Labs.
我真希望你之前就告诉我
I just--I wish you would've told me.
有时  我感觉一切都很不真实
I didn't--it hardly feels real sometimes.
我们很高兴有人能帮你
We're just glad you're getting help.
是的
Yeah.
那我们没事了吧
So, we're good?
是的  没事了
Yeah, we're good.
-来杯咖啡吗  -好的
- Coffee? - Yeah.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - You are welcome.
一位有良知的科学家
不是吧
Come on.
哈里森·威尔斯
Harrison Wells.
你都了解他什么
What do you know about him?
你知道什么
What do you know?
我所知道的都在那个盘里
Everything I know is in that drive.
我发誓
I swear.
所有的
Everything?
所有的  拿走吧
Everything! Just take it!
你真的会成为世纪人物的
You really were on to the story of the century.
一位有良知的科学家
反正这个世纪会这样的
this century, anyway.
你觉得我是不是犯错了
Do you think I made a mistake
把史纳特放走
letting Snart go?
我觉得你做了当时认为是正确的事
I think you did what you felt was right in the moment.
而且说真的  巴里
And really, Barry,
这是我们所期望的最好的事了
that's the best any of us can hope for.
我们还是感谢上帝时间没被修改吧
Now, let's be thankful the timeline remains intact.
我老是忘记
I keep forgetting.
我想要问你件事
I've been meaning to ask you.
记者梅森·布里奇失踪
是关于西蒙的
It's about Simon...
你说什么  艾伦先生
You were saying, Mr. Allen?
记者梅森·布里奇失踪
没什么  抱歉
Nothing. Sorry.
晚安  威尔斯博士
Night, Dr. Wells.
晚安  巴里
Good night. Barry.
巴仔  怎么了
Bar, what's up?
为什么这么晚让我来这见你
Why do you want me to meet you up here so late?
我觉得你对威尔斯博士的想法
I think that maybe you're right
可能是对的
about Dr. Wells.
哪些想法
Which part?
所有的
All of it.